question number one says in terms of
intermolecular forces which of the
following compounds is only capable of
London dispersion so we have different
kinds of intermolecular forces possible
there could be molecules that do dipole
dipole interactions for example but one
of these is only capable of London
dispersion in order to check out what's
going on we want to draw these molecules
out so we can identify what kinds of
bonds are present ch3
ch2 we've got that o group there
ch3f we got that Central carbon atom and
then we've got the F and then we've got
some hydrogens so that's got that
tetrahedral geometry ch2 ch2 that means
that we have a double bond because every
carbon is going to have four bonds there
and then we have hbr so what do we
notice about the types of bonds that are
present in order for something to do
dipole dipole interactions we have to
have some Bond dipoles we need to have
some polar bonds there can we find some
polar bonds
most of these do have polar bonds so for
example on ethanol there we've got an O
bond this is partial minus this is
partial plus so that is a polar bond and
that Bond dipole is going to be able to
interact with other bond dipoles to make
dipole dipole interactions in this case
they're specifically hydrogen bonds and
then over here we have a polar CF Bond
right this is also polarized towards the
Florine the carbon is going to be
partially positive the Florine is
partially negative the same thing with
hbr we've got a partially positive H and
we've got a partially minus bromine and
so those are examples of polar bonds
that are going to be able to make
electrostatic interactions with other
polar bonds that will be dipole dipole
interactions or hydrogen bonds that are
stronger interactions than London
dispersion however over here we don't
have any of those with ch2 ch2 these are
all non-polar bonds so carbon carbon
bonds are obviously non-polar completely
non-polar and CH bonds there's not
enough an electro negativity difference
there to consider that a polar bond so
we would say that these are all
non-polar bonds and therefore it is not
able to do any dipo dipole interactions
or anything of that magnitude we're
going to say C right here that is ch2
ch2 that is the only molecule that is
only capable of London dispersion